A little pause... and we are back.
Those are my grandfather's things!
Where do you think you're taking them?
Honorable grandson, we... I
said, where are you taking them?
They belong to my grandfather!
Uh, well, these things...
they're just in the way, you see,
so we thought it would be
best to put them somewhere safe.
What do you mean, just in the way?
You shouldn't even be touching that stuff!
Who gave you permission?
Well, we have to make room for the next
Hokage.
Uh, what?
Yeah, it's done.
The fifth Hokage has finally been chosen.
It's a big relief to the whole village.
Now the one that's been chosen
is moving in, so we have to... No!
No way!
It's too soon for a new Hokage!
My grandfather was everything to this
village!
Seven.
There are seven birds within fifty meters
of pillar number two.
What do you want, Tenten?
Neji!
Hey, haven't you heard the news?
Lady Tsunade's returned!
It's really her!
Don't you want to see her?
No, not really.
Not right now.
Huh?
Hmm.
There were eight birds.
Listen carefully, Tenten.
Lady Tsunade, we must send
word to the Feudal Lord that
the fifth Hokage has
officially arrived in the village.
All the preparations must begin at once
for the installation ceremony.
Can't we just skip the ceremonies?
They're such a bore.
Okay, it comes with the job, I guess.
One of the perks of being Hokage.
Genma.
Here.
Alba.
Send out the word.
The village must be made
aware that in a few days
from now, we will officially
welcome the fifth hokage.
Okay.
I hate all this.
My body's sore and stiff.
All I want is to sit down and relax with a
nice hot cup of tea.
Yes, but lady... Not
so fast, grandma!
Before you start sucking
down some tea, isn't
there something
you're forgetting about?
What would that be?
Come on!
Are you kidding me?
What about Kakashi-sensei and Sasuke and
Bushi-brow?
Oh yeah, I did forget about them.
Well, if it isn't Naruto.
Hmm?
Shikamaru?
What are you doing here?
Shouldn't you be somewhere stuffing your
face?
How about you?
You're usually still asleep this time of
day.
Very funny.
My dad asked me to come along with him,
but don't ask me why.
Hmm?
Hey, do they know each other?
Greetings, Lady Tsunade.
It's been a long time.
You're that kid from the Nara family.
Hope you're still taking good care of the
deer.
I made a lot of money.
I got good medicine out of those antlers.
Oh yes, the deer are fine.
Who's the blonde girl?
And why is she talking to my dad like
she's his boss?
Didn't you hear?
She's the fifth Hokage.
Huh?
And she's no girl.
She's actually an old lady in her fifties.
Huh?
I'll see you again soon, no doubt.
Yes, my lady.
So long.
We're going to the infirmary.
I'll catch you later, Shikamaru.
I'll show you the killer new technique I
picked up.
That's really the fifth Hokage?
Watch it, Shikamaru.
That woman is one of the strongest ninja
you'll ever meet.
Don't let her good looks fool you.
Yeah?
After all, there's a reason she's the only
female among the legendary Sannin.
Okay... but I mean a woman, Hokage?
Not to sound prejudiced or anything,
but is that such a good idea?
Hmm...
Come on, you know what they're like.
You can never figure them out.
You never know where you stand with them.
The smallest things can put you on their
bad side.
And always playing their
little mind games with
you, trying to get you
to do what they want.
They're just a big pain, basically.
Hmm...
Listen, Shikamaru.
Hmm?
Keep in mind that without women,
you and I wouldn't even exist.
And take my word for it, they make men
better people than we'd ever be without them.
Unlike us, even the strongest of them isn't
afraid to be gentle with the man she loves.
It's funny to hear him talking like this.
Tied to Mom's apron strings the way he is.
Someday you'll understand what I'm talking
about.
Oh, we better hurry up.
Let's finish up our business here and get
back.
You know how your mother will chew us out
if we're late.
Come on, Shikamaru.
May I come in?
Who are you?
Whoever she is, she's beautiful.
Sakura!
You'll never believe it!
She's gonna make everything okay again!
Don't worry, Sasuke's gonna be all right
now.
Naruto...
Those flowers weren't picked the same day.
Looks like she's been visiting him for a
while now.
You must be the one Gai-sensei told me
about.
Oh, please, if you can save
Sasuke... Well, I'll see what I can do.
Sasuke!
Oh, Sasuke!
Hey, you're back!
Huh?
ması Hm.
The little tough guy has a soft spot,
I see.
Come on!
You're not done!
We're done!
Disgraceful.
To be taken completely out of the game by
two low-life punks like that...
I thought you were supposed to be the
best.
Sorry to disappoint you.
Okay, that's Kakashi-sensei!
Now just one more and you're all done!
Ruck Lee!
He's right next door!
Next door!
LEE!
Look who's here to see you!
It's Lady Tsunade!
Is this one of your students, guy?
Yes!
He's more than a student, he's like a son.
I see.
Naruto.
Huh?
Do you really have time to be dawdling
around here?
You're right!
I almost forgot I'm supposed to meet
Iruka-sensei!
Better run along.
Right!
I'll let you take it from here!
All right!
Hey there, Naruto!
Finally, Iruka-sensei!
Where you been?
I'm late, sorry.
It's all the preparations for the fifth
Hokage.
Well, okay, whatever.
No one will hold it against you if you
give up on being a shinobi.
But... but you're not serious!
You're exaggerating, right, Lady Tsunade?
Huh?
But... but you're not serious!
You're exaggerating, right, Lady Tsunade?
Huh?
But you're not serious!
You're exaggerating, right, Lady Tsunade?
His injuries have left numerous bone
fragments embedded in his spinal column.
It's a miracle he can still move at all.
He's physically incapable of carrying out
the duties of a shinobi.
This is some kind of test, right?
You don't really mean that.
Even if I were able to operate...
Don't listen to her, Lee!
That's not Lady Tsunade!
It's an impostor!
It's some kind of demon that's transformed
itself to look like her!
Who are you?!
You!
What do you want?
So I have no chance?
It is hopeless?
No one but me could even attempt the
operation.
But even with my skills, the risks would
be enormous.
What risks?
The chances of it being successful are
50-50 at best.
And if it should fail...
He'll die.
I will never give up, Gai-sensei!
I will be back stronger than ever!
This is horrible, Gai-sensei!
Why are you making me eat this?
They're very rare Chinese herbal medicine
balls.
I'm told that eating 100 or so should heal
your injuries.
Then I do not care what they taste like!
I will eat them all!
Whatever it takes!
I don't think they met all of them in one
day!
It's best if you give up being a shinobi.
Find a different path.
Lee...
If I had known you were gonna do this,
I would have never let you see them.
Don't say that!
I understand your pain.
Believe me, I get no pleasure from this.
But he needs to know the truth,
and to know it now.
A choice has to be made.
Putting it off won't make it any easier.
I want to show I can be a splendid ninja
as well!
Even if I do not have ninjutsu or
genjutsu!
I want to prove it to the whole world!
That's enough now!
We don't want to have to break it down!
Go ahead and try it!
See what happens!
I'm the grandson of the third Hokage!
If you go against me, you're going against
my...
My grandpa...
You'll be going against the Hokage!
Lady Tsunade has important work to do and
she can't do it until she gets in there.
Pepper's full of bombs!
And you'll get worse if you try coming in!
The whole place is booby-trapped!
Venerable grandson, even you...
There are some things even you can't get
away with!
Now come out of there!
Shut up and go away!
Isn't it a little early for all this
racket?
It's giving me a screaming headache.
Lady Tsunade... Lady Tsunade...
Huh?
You two can't handle one little kid?
Well...
Get him out of there!
But ma'am, he's the grandson of the third
Hokage!
What do I care?
I'm the granddaughter of the first Hokage!
I'm the one you need to worry about now!
From what I can see, it might do the brat
some good to be roughed up a little.
Now get him out of there!
Right.
Wait!
Don't!
Tamaruto...
Hold on.
Just wait a second.
I don't know exactly what's going on here,
but don't be too rough on Konohamaru, huh?
Please, Grandma Tsunade!
He's a friend of yours, is he?
Mm-hmm.
Don't worry, I can get him out!
Just let me talk to him!
He'll listen to me!
I want him out of there by the end of the
day!
End of the day?
But... Lady Tsunade!
Wait!
Look at this place.
Not a single gambling hall anywhere.
Well, you don't have time for that anyway.
There's an awful lot of work waiting to be
done.
Nowhere to gamble.
Or get a drink.
What a boring little dump a Leaf Village
is.
It's no fun at all.
Just like the third Hokage.
Lady Tsunade!
Oh, I'm exhausted.
I just want to sit down and have a drink
somewhere.
Isn't that too much to ask?
Huh?
If that's what you want.
If it's absolutely
necessary, I'll find you a
place where you can
have a drink, all right?
Really?
But only if you promise to get to work.
Hm.
Eight D-rank missions.
Three C-rank missions.
Exactly like Kurenai's own team.
It's not hard to see what the third Hokage
was thinking.
This squad is a mirror image of their
parents' team.
I see.
Oh, look how well-balanced this squad is.
Each member with his or her own specialty.
If we can't support them,
no matter how tough it
gets, he can't imagined
having a job in high school.
Boy, is that a cost to you still Wow
that's a surprise coming from the outside,
ah, ok.
I'll help you find more key.
Listen.
This strengthened my brain, right?
Nature.
Now I've officially had it!
Game's over, kid!
With my new powers, I
can easily blast those doors
down, though I was hoping
not to have to use them!
You're too much help!
Grandma Tsunade!
Wait, be careful!
Oh, no!
Oh!
I should have never let her out of my
sight for a minute.
Oh...
Oink!
O-O-Oink!
Lead me to her, Ton-Ton!
Revitalizing the cellular structure...
Revitalizing the cellular structure... Huh...
Aha!
So there you are!
We caught you.
Shhh!
Lady Tsunade, are you actually studying?
Oink!
Be quiet, will you?
I'm trying to concentrate here.
What did you say?!
You've never concentrated on anything but
gambling!
Huh?
That sounded like Shizune.
Oh, just calm down.
I was thinking about that medical ninja,
Kabuto.
Remember?
What about him?
Specifically, his body's ability to create
new cells.
If I could apply that technique to a
patient...
You mean Rock Lee, don't you?
Even if it only increases his chances from
50 to 51%, I think it may be worth a try.
Lady Tsunade, the success of that technique
depends so much on the person doing it.
There's no guarantee that you'd be able to
pull it off.
Only one way to find out.
I mean, I am the fifth Hokage,
after all.
Oh...
There's no way out of it, Konohamaru.
I must go.
I am the third Hokage, after all.
If that's what it means to be Hokage,
then quit.
Everyone in this village is family to me.
Protecting the family, that's what it
means to be Hokage.
Wait!
Grandpa!
I can't do this!
Just this once.
I'll make an exception.
Where are we going, Konohamaru?
What's the matter, don't you want to see
Grandma Tsunade?
Nope.
Hmm.
I am the fifth Hokage, after all.
There's no way out of it, Konohamaru.
I am the third Hokage, after all.
There's no way out of it.
I'm the honorable grandson, after all.
Huh?
I mean, I'm Konohamaru of the Leaf
Village!
Hey!
Where are you going?
Wait up, Konohamaru!
What the heck's gotten into him?
Hey!
Konohamaru!
What is it, Lady Tsunade?
Oh, nothing.
Gojutsu!
Transformation Jutsu!
Hey, kid.
Huh?
The glory of youth is in its unbridled
passion.
You just keep chippin' away at its sun,
you'll make a splendid shinobi someday.
Who is he?
He is so confident!
Grab hold of life by both horns!
That's what youth is for!
Goodbye!
Hahaha!
Huh?
I thought I'd find you here.
Gai!
Gai-sensei!
How did you know where to look for me?
I know everything about you, Lee.
I hear you've been skipping out on your
physical therapy.
You know better.
Back when I first made
genin, I swore I would
realize my every dream
right here on this spot.
I swore.
And Neji laughed at me back then.
But I meant every word of it.
I am going to be a splendid ninja as well!
Even if I do not have any ninjutsu or
genjutsu!
I want to prove it to the whole world!
I remember you told me that
with the right amount of passion
and some healthy competition,
we would all be great ninja.
And to make it happen, we would have to
work for it.
I knew I could do it.
Transform!
Back in the academy, there was not a
single person, sensei or student,
who said that kind of thing to me.
I understood him.
Your words were a relief.
Just as I was starting to feel lost,
you lifted the fog from my eyes.
I knew.
All I had to do was work harder.
You're the girl I was looking for.
I've never seen anyone like you,
Neji.
Everyone knows who I am.
When I said that hard work
was no match against true
genius, you told me I
was a genius of hard work.
Thanks to you and your
encouragement, I've finally
learned the importance
of believing in myself.
The chances of surgery being successful
are 50-50 at best, and if it fails,
he'll die.
But... but it is not the same this time.
Even if I believe in
myself and try as hard as I
can, it will not make
the slightest difference!
Gai-sensei, please tell me what to do!
Tell me, Gai-sensei.
Do you think maybe I can follow in your
footsteps someday?
How come I am the only one being punished
like this?
I have my own dreams to protect.
I do not care if it means dying.
I follow my ninjo, my ninja way!
Tell me, what should I do?
The Eight Inner Gates.
A forbidden jutsu one can die using.
What do I do?
I am prepared for the worst.
Teach me the forbidden jutsu, whatever it
takes for my dream!
That means everything to me!
The time is right.
Head for the Leaf Village.
Now.
You're going to be okay.
You know, your injury could have been much
more serious.
Naruto was relieved, too.
So, uh...
You must be hungry, Sasuke.
Is there something special you want to
eat?
Well, I'll go pick something up for you.
To be honest with you, I don't know what
to do.
With the final exam being
suspended, it was the opinion of
many that none of the students
should pass this time around.
And that includes you.
However, I hear that
the Third Hokage had
nothing but the highest
praise for your match.
It seems he meant to recommend you for
Chunin.
In fact, all those who observed the fight
and your proctors felt the same.
So, in this case, my opinion doesn't
really matter.
From this day forth, I
hope you will strive to
achieve a level of excellence
worthy of that headband.
Congratulations.
As of this moment, you stand a Chunin.
Wow!
You know, even a guy
who's as lazy as you are
somehow seems
respectable all of a sudden.
It doesn't suit you.
It's not that funny.
Funny or not, let's have
a toast and celebrate
Shikamaru's outstanding
promotion to Chunin.
Yeah!
Let's eat!
Choji, hey!
Lay off of the meat!
We're about to have a toast!
Oh, sorry.
I just didn't want it to get burned.
There's plenty of meat for everyone.
Dig in.
All right!
You're gonna end up in the hospital again,
Choji.
I mean, haven't you ever heard of savoring
your food?
Don't worry.
I figure the more bites I eat, the
more bites I get to savor, right?
Oh, come on, Choji!
That's the last piece of meat,
and I cooked it!
The last piece of meat.
This bite shall be the
most sacred bite of our
entire meal and must be
consumed with utmost care.
So back off, sister.
I'm not handing this morsel over to
anyone.
Why do you have to act like such an
idiot?!
Choji!
Pulling ridiculous stunts like this is why
everyone always makes fun of you!
You are such a fan!
Don't say that word.
And Choji, settle down.
A meal's not the same as a battle.
Stop being such a pain.
We're trying to relax here.
Vulgar.
Short-tempered.
Lazy.
I wonder if these kids are gonna make it.
Particularly.
Choji, you've gotta stop thinking about
food.
Do a little training for once.
Hmm...
Go away.
You don't interest me at the moment.
Naruto is the one you're really after.
Yo, Sakura!
I'm here!
Naruto...
What a peaceful little village.
Can't say much for their security,
though.
Heh.
This village really ought to be taught a
lesson.
We could just stroll right in there and
wipe them all out.
Don't even start, Sakon.
That's right.
We're not here to wipe anybody out.
What's wrong, Tubby?
You scared?
Why don't you do us all a favor and go
back to bed?
Alright, Hiyuya.
Everybody just calm down.
We all know what our mission is,
right?
Look, I brought you some apples.
You like them, right?
Here, don't they look delicious?
That's weird.
I wonder where I put that knife I had
before.
It's right in front of you, Sakura.
Oh.
You're so lame getting all scatterbrained
just cause you're around Sasuke.
Why do you have to come in here on your
own?
Naruto.
NAN!
RU!
TAO!
CHUKE!
FUZUBAKI BORAI!
NAN!
RU!
TAO!
CHUKE!
FUZUBAKI BORAI!
Geez, Naruto.
Will you knock it off already?
KAMARING JUJU!
Sakura.
I swear I'll protect you.
Okay, okay.
Don't hit me.
Sasuke, thank you.
I mean, you know, you protected me from
the sand, right?
No.
It wasn't me who rescued you.
It was Naruto.
You're still too weak.
You don't have enough hate.
And you know something?
You never will.
Done.
All peeled and ready.
I'll cut it so it's easier to eat.
Here!
Wanna try one?
Ow!
What the?
Sasuke?
What the heck's going on?
You.
Naruto.
Yeah, I'm listening.
I want you to fight me.
Fight me now.
What?
We're in a hospital.
You just got patched up by Grandma
Tsunade.
What are you talking about?
Shut up and fight!
Sasuke... Do you really
think you saved me?
I don't care if she's the fifth Hokage.
You shouldn't have gotten her involved in
this.
What?
After all, you did say you wanted to
fight.
Well, now it looks like you've got your
chance.
That is, unless you've chickened out.
Hey!
S-Sasuke!
Wait!
Don't do this!
Naruto, say something!
This is crazy!
Sasuke!
Actually, this is perfect!
I was just thinking about how I wanted to
kick your butt!
Follow me.
What's this weird feeling?
My lower belly's all tight!
I wanna fight you, too.
And... and I'm getting chills!
Hmph.
What's so funny?
I'm not laughing cause it's funny!
I'm just psyched!
Cause I know that today is the day when I
finally beat you!
What did you say?
Don't talk nonsense, you inept loser!
I won't be such a loser after I win today,
will I?
Go away.
You don't interest me at the moment.
You.
An idiot like you has no business acting
all high and mighty!
Ha!
What happened to the comm-controlled
Sasuke?
Am I making you nervous?
It looks like you picked
a fight with me and
now you're too scared
to go through with it!
Is that it?
Let's just do this.
Put on your headband and we will.
I'll wait.
Not to worry.
I don't need that thing.
Just do it!
Come on!
There's no reason to put it on.
Cause you won't be able to make a scratch
on my forehead.
That's not the point!
Come on, you know
putting your headband on is a
testament to fighting on
equal terms as a Leaf Shinobi!
There you go, acting all high and mighty
again.
You don't honestly believe that we're
equals.
Heck yeah I do!
All this time I've never once thought that
I was inferior to you in any way!
You're a complete embarrassment!
Only because next to me... you're
embarrassed at how weak you are!
Isn't that right Sasuke?
Naruto!
Sasuke!
Don't get cocky and let your guard down!
I've had just about enough of this!
Multi Shadow Claw Jutsu!
FIRE STYLE!
FIRE BOMB JUJU!
Oh!
Naruto!
How did he?
What juju is that?
Please, stop this!
I'll win no matter what!
I'm not finished with you yet!
Stop it!
What do you two think you're doing?
That was a little intense for just a
sparring match, wasn't it?
What's wrong with you two?
What were you thinking?
Were you really going to kill him,
Sasuke?
That Chidori... it was not the size you'd
aim at a comrade from the Leaf Village.
When are you finally going to grow up,
Sasuke?
Did meeting up with Itachi cause this?
Dammit!
Naruto... how far have you...
I'm assuming it was you who taught him
that technique.
I know you want to protect him from the
Akatsuki.
But still, to entrust him with a jutsu
like that...
After all, he could have killed Sasuke.
Aren't you a fine one to talk?
Teaching the Chidori to someone like
Sasuke...
I knew he was a hothead.
But I never imagined he'd
be willing to use a jutsu
that powerful against a
comrade from his own village.
To Naruto, Sasuke is a comrade and a rival
at the same time.
In fact, it's the competition between them
that keeps him going.
That's why he won't stand for it when
Sasuke tries to belittle him.
He's been dogging
Sasuke's steps every inch of
the way since their first
days at the academy.
As far as Naruto's concerned, what you and
I think doesn't matter.
There's only one person whose approval he
really cares about.
Sasuke.
On the other hand, it's hard
for Sasuke to watch Naruto's
strength and skills develop
at such an astonishing rate.
He's come along so fast, Sasuke must feel
like he's standing still.
You mean revenge.
His hatred of Itachi may be driving him on
too fast.
Sasuke can't acknowledge Naruto's
abilities.
He's afraid that if he does acknowledge
them, he somehow diminishes his own.
It can be hard work maintaining a rivalry.
Well, it's not a very healthy rivalry.
It's time I gave somebody a talking to.
Right.
I'll be right back.
I'll leave Naruto to you, then.
Well, I have a mission.
And then there's that Chidori business.
Sakura.
It'll be alright, don't you worry.
We'll soon have them back to their old
selves again.
Cheer up, okay?
I'll see you soon.
What is it, Naruto?
Listen, Sakura.
This is between us.
Stay out of it.
You're still too weak.
You don't have enough hate.
And you know something?
You never will.
I like that look in his eyes.
I'm sorry, but I'm sorry.
I'm testing everyone's luck.
You know what?
When I'm at it, I'll meet you.
Be careful.
Actually, I'll be here any time.
Well, that's a good start.
I'll leave you to it.
What?
Shut up!
What makes you think you know anything
about it?
It's easy for you to talk.
You have no idea!
Easy.
Just try to calm down.
Maybe if I was to kill the most important
people in your life, everyone who's ever
meant anything, maybe then I'd listen to
you.
Because maybe then you'd have some idea
how I feel!
Hmm.
It's an interesting theory, but I'm afraid
you're a little late to put it to the test.
Everyone you're talking about has already
been killed.
I've been around longer than you have,
kid.
And I've seen my share of troubles.
You're not the only one who knows what
it's like to lose somebody.
So, it looks like neither of us has led a
charmed life exactly, have we?
Still, we're not all that bad off.
At least you and I have been lucky enough
to find new comrades to help fill the void.
Anyway... I do
know how you feel.
With the Chidori, you've been granted a
gift of awesome power.
It's not a power to be used against your
comrades, or to seek vengeance.
I think, in your heart of hearts,
you know what it's for.
Okay, end of lecture.
You decide whether what I'm saying hits
the mark or not.
The one with him is Kakashi.
I've heard about him.
We'd better hold off for a bit.
Well, if you're so scared of him,
why don't I just go in by myself?
He doesn't look that tough to me.
I'm with you.
I bet the two of us could tear that Leaf
Shinobi apart.
Did I sound like I wanted your help?
Butt out, birdbrain!
Man, it's no wonder you never had a
boyfriend.
You're such a-Shut it, fatso!
Just the two of us...
What is he, a... ...a...
...a...
...a... ...a...
...a little goodbye?
Let's go back.
Alright.
We both made it.
We climbed all the way up to the top.
What's wrong, Sakura?
Look, there's something I need to talk to
you about, Naruto.
So if you still want that date
you've always wanted... Huh?
What do I do?
Dammit!
We are the Sound Ninja Four.
We're here on orders from Lord Orochimaru.
You guys might want to think twice about
doing this.
Because I'm in a really bad mood right
now.
Oh, just stop all of your prattling,
you little weakling.
Did he call me weak?
Come on, kid.
I want to play do-re-mi on those ribs of
yours till they crack!
What?
Orochimaru left a curse mark on Sasuke's
body?
Yeah.
And he said Sasuke would come looking for
him, hoping to find more power.
I see.
I didn't realize that had happened.
Orochimaru, huh?
Yeah, I ran into him not too long ago.
You did?
He was incredibly powerful.
Guy is bad news.
Come on, everything will be fine.
Sasuke would never let a guy like that
sink his claws into him.
He's already a powerhouse.
It's not like he needs that kind of help,
you know.
Ah!
You should come with us.
Lord Orochimaru offers you power.
What is your purpose in this life?
To stay here in this backwater village,
hiding with your little friends?
Surely you haven't forgotten, Itachi
Uchiha?
Don't lose sight of your purpose.
Life in this village is little more than
bondage for you.
So sever your ties and leave this pathetic
place.
If you can do that, there will be no limit
to the power you can wield.
Remember your purpose!
It's the middle of the night.
What are you hanging around here for?
This is the only road out of the village.
You should go to bed.
Why, Sasuke?
Why won't you ever tell me anything?
Why is it always silence with you?
You've never shared a single thing with
me!
Why should I have to tell you anything?
Just keep your nose out of my business.
It's none of your concern.
I know you hate me.
Even in the beginning you could never
stand me.
Remember?
Back when we made Ginnine and we were
assigned to our three-man squads?
Yeah, sure.
I mean, it was so long ago, right?
But still, that's the day when it all
began.
It was the start of you and me.
And Naruto.
And Kakashi-sensei.
The four of us started going on missions.
It was rough back then.
Every day was such a challenge.
More than anything...
It was so much fun!
I know about your clan, Sasuke.
I do.
But seeking revenge...
That won't bring anyone happiness.
Nobody at all.
Not you.
And not me.
I knew it.
I'm not the same as you.
I'm traveling a path the rest of you can't
follow.
I know that the four of us have worked
together.
And for a while, I thought I could take
that road instead.
But in the end, I've decided on revenge.
That's always been my reason for living.
I'll never be like you and Naruto.
Don't do this, Sasuke!
You don't have to be alone!
You told me that day how painful a thing
solitude can be.
I understand that pain now.
I have a family.
And friends.
But... if you were gone, Sasuke...
It would be the same thing for me.
As being all alone.
This is a new beginning.
Each of us has a new path lying before us.
Sasuke!
I'm so in love with you, I can't even
stand it!
If you would only be with me!
I promise, I'd never let you regret it!
Every day will be a joy!
I can give you happiness!
I'll do anything for you, Sasuke!
So please!
I'm begging you, don't walk away!
I'll even help get your revenge!
I'll do whatever it takes to make it
happen, I swear!
So stay here... with me... and if you
can't... then take me with you, Sasuke!
You haven't changed.
You're still annoying.
Don't leave me!
If you go, I'll scream and...
Sakura...
Thank you for everything.
Sasuke...
We've been waiting for you, Sasuke.
So what's with the change in attitude?
It had already been decided that the
moment you abandoned the village,
you would become our new leader.
Please forgive the rudeness we displayed
earlier.
Hmph.
Now I'll ask you some questions.
I don't care about that.
I won't let you go to a fool's abode.
Sasuke... I will help you.
Okay!
I'll be careful.
Sasuke...
She forgot these papers.
She should go get them.
What is it?
Hey, wake up.
You're gonna catch a cold if you sleep out
here.
No... No...
Sasuke, no!
What did you say?
Are you sure of that?
Yes.
We heard this from Sakura herself.
There's no reason to doubt what she told
us.
So that's what that wretch is after.
He's going for the Uchiha's powers.
Izumo, Kotetsu.
There's somebody that I need to see.
Would you hurry up and eat, Shikamaru?
Your dad has an important mission to get
to.
If you just sit there, he won't have time
for morning training.
Yeah, yeah...
Don't talk, just eat!
From the second I get up, it's nag,
nag, nag.
Now who would be visiting us so early in
the morning?
Hey, Dad.
What is it?
What on earth made you want to marry such
a crabby woman like Mom?
That's a good question.
Even a crab like your mom can be gentle
sometimes.
She has her moments.
No...
That's the reason?
Shikamaru!
Lady Hokage has sent a messenger to see
you.
Late last night, Sasuke Uchiha left the
Hidden Leaf Village.
Huh?
And... we're quite certain he's headed for
the Hidden Sound Village.
He just left?
How could this happen?
Simple.
Orochimaru must have him in his clutches.
Huh?
What?
Wait!
That doesn't make any sense.
What does Sasuke have to gain by talking
to someone as depraved as Orochimaru?
At this point, his motive doesn't matter.
We need to deal with it quickly.
I've decided it's time
for you to carry out
your first mission as
a Chunin, Shikamaru.
So all I gotta do is bring Sasuke back?
As long as none of our enemies are with
him, it shouldn't be that big a deal.
Yes, that's your mission.
But it must be accomplished without delay.
And you may find it a more dangerous task
than you think.
Huh?
There's a strong possibility that Sasuke
is being guarded by Orochimaru's men.
Damn.
This is gonna be a real pain in the ass.
What happened to Sasuke anyway?
I used to look up to him and now he's
joined up with the bad guys.
This really stinks.
Well, if we're gonna be facing
opposition, I'm gonna need
to request a team composed
exclusively of Jonin and Chunin.
I can't honor that request.
What?
And why not?
You already know the answer.
As I'm sure you're aware, most of the
Jonin have been sent out on missions.
Only a handful stayed behind to defend in
case of attack.
Go round up any skilled Genin you feel are
up to the job.
You have 30 minutes to leave this village.
Hold on.
There is one person I strongly recommend
you include.
No way!
You gotta be kidding!
You just woke up, and you're already this
annoying?
Why'd she want me to bring this guy?
Sasuke, you jerk!
Hey, hold on a second!
I'll go get dressed!
Hmm...
So, uh, besides me, have you come up with
any other top-notch guys to ask?
A few.
Wake up, will ya?
You said top-notch guys, right?
Plan B, I guess.
Wait, Plan B is potato chips?
They're barbecue flavor.
Feel free to help out.
Hmm...
Now.
Even for a bag of potato chips,
I refuse to let anyone have the last bite!
Choji and I have been on the same team for
a long time.
We work well together, so asking him's a
no-brainer.
I get it!
You know him!
But for this kind of
thing, don't you think
your first choice should
be someone like Shino?
Man, you always have to yell.
Not on your life!
Shino can't do it.
He's off on some special mission with his
father right now.
Hey, wait!
Not them, too!
Yep, they're on the team.
I see.
Sounds like an interesting job.
I guess getting up early to walk the dogs
pays off sometimes.
Hey, Shikamaru, is there anybody else?
I wish we had time to find some more guys,
but we're late already.
If we don't run across
anybody else on our way
out of the village, I
suppose it'll just be us.
Yes, I understand.
Yeah, it's kind of a drag, but I figure
the more guys we have, the better, so...
Why now, of all times...
Lee, it's up to you.
You do what you must do.
All right!
Come on!
Let's get going, everybody!
Follow me!
Um... Hey, Naruto.
I'm kind of supposed to be the platoon
leader here.
I know it's a drag, but...
You really think you're the best person to
direct this operation?
You don't seem very reliable to me.
What's up with you acting like you're in
charge all of a sudden, Naruto?
I mean, taking orders
from somebody as lazy as
Shikamaru doesn't exactly
thrill me either, but still...
But none of you get to
decide who's the leader here,
because Shikamaru is the
only one of us who's a Chunin.
That means the elders of
the village clearly believe
he's got what it takes to
call the shots on this one.
If that's the case, then perhaps you should
start coming up with some sort of a plan.
From what I heard,
Sasuke's gone to the enemy,
and there's a real chance
they could ambush us.
Well, for starters, this
is a rescue operation,
so we'll be in the
position of pursuit.
Which means the enemy already has an
important advantage over us.
That said, I'm arranging us in a deployment
formation that can respond to the enemy.
If any of you don't follow my exact
orders, we're all gonna die.
Okay, we'll go with a single-file strike
formation.
As we all know, the most important position
is the spearhead, so that's gonna be...
Kiba, you're up front.
With all the walks you
and Akamaru go on, you're
the most familiar with
the Land of Fire's terrain.
And with that sensitive nose of yours...
You'll be able to track
Sasuke's scent, while
sniffing out any booby
traps the enemy may have set.
Moreover, because we'll have two sets of
eyes up front, you and Akamaru will be
more effective in protecting our
single-file line from an assault.
Second in line will be yours truly,
Platoon Leader.
From that position,
I'll be able to direct
everyone behind me
using silent hand signals.
And because I'm so close to Kiba, I'll
be in position to react to any situation.
In the middle, the number three position
is Naruto.
The middle of the line is the perfect
location for you because you're the most
capable of executing quick moves either in
front of you or behind you.
You're the cornerstone, and you have the
Shadow Clone Jutsu.
Fourth in line is Choji.
Choji, you might not
have any speed, but your
striking power is the greatest
of the Platoon members.
Kiba, myself, and Naruto will launch a
surprise attack.
Then you'll swoop in and finish him off.
You're the second wave of our assault.
Finally, on the end will be you,
Neji.
Your position is most difficult.
Rear lookout.
I want you to use your Byakugan to constantly
scan ahead for weakness in our ranks.
Got it?
Then take a look at this.
This diagram shows exactly what part of
the perimeter you're responsible for.
Kiba watches the front.
I'm responsible for a wider forward view.
Naruto's got the left.
Choji, the right.
And Neji, using your Byakugan,
you cover the entire area to the rear.
Alright, now I think I should familiarize
myself with our arms and weaponry.
I'll need to check out
all of the ninja tools
each of you plan on
carrying into battle.
That way I'll know what we have.
Are there any questions?
Even though he has just
assembled this team, he has
already created the best
possible formation for them.
Since no one has anything to add,
I save the most important thing for last.
For as long as I've known him, Sasuke
and I haven't exactly been close buddies.
In fact, I don't really like him at all.
All the same, Sasuke's a ninja belonging
to the Hidden Leaf Village.
He's a comrade.
And I'll put my life on the line to help
him.
That's the way of our village.
I know I usually seem like a pretty lazy
guy.
But not today.
Because now I'm responsible for your
lives, too.
Wow, I never thought I'd see Shikamaru
acting like a Chunin.
Very impressive.
Okay, as soon as we check our gear,
we'll go.
Show me your weapons.
Sasuke would never let a guy like that
sink his claws into him.
I mean, he's already a total powerhouse.
It's not like he needs that kind of help,
you know.
Don't worry.
I guarantee it.
Dammit.
Why, Sasuke?
All right.
Let's move out.
Wait!
Are you all right?
Lady Hokage told me everything.
Sorry, Sakura.
I can't take you on this mission.
I know you tried.
But even you couldn't convince Sasuke,
could you?
Now our only option is for me to find him
and force him to come back to the village.
I'm sorry.
But there's nothing else you can do for
him.
I'm sorry.
Naruto...
This is a... once-in-a-lifetime request.
Just bring him home.
Please bring Sasuke back to me.
I did everything I could.
I tried, but I couldn't stop him from
leaving the village.
At this point, there's only one person who
can stop him.
Only one who can save him.
Naruto, it's all up to you.
Oh gosh, Sakura.
You must really care about Sasuke,
huh?
I get it.
I can see that deep down this must be
really painful for you.
I know you must be suffering.
Sakura, I want to ask you something.
Huh?
Naruto, what do you think of him?
He knows about my feelings and he
purposely gets in the way.
It's almost like he enjoys interfering and
making me feel bad.
Despite what he says, he doesn't
understand one single thing about me.
He's just annoying.
Naruto, thank you so much.
Don't you worry one bit!
I'm gonna bring Sasuke back!
I promise that on my life, Sakura!
More than anyone else, you always
understood me.
You've always been there when I needed
help.
Naruto...
was normally the one who never needed your
help.
Whoa!
Honda Naruto!
That's quite an insult.
Are you sure you can promise her that we
will save him?!
Sure!
When I ask for this, you can count on me,
I'm on budget for the ninja way!
Well, come on!
I'll come to you and solve it when I
finish my adjustment, come along!
Huh?
Hey, theнимu... Right!
A little pause... and we are back.